Fulton Lewis III Papers
Fulton Lewis III Papers
1947-1967
Lewis, Fulton, 1936-
2.5 linear ft.
Papers of the American journalist, son of broadcast and print journalist Fulton Lewis (1903-1966). Correspondence (1966-1967); manuscripts (1966); published material, principally newsletters (1966-1967).
149131
Biographical History
Fulton Lewis III (1936-) is an American journalist, son of broadcast and print journalist Fulton Lewis (1903-1966). Among other achievements, he covered numerous conflicts in Vietnam, Biafra, Rhodesia, and elsewhere, and served as Director of Research for the House Un-American Activities Committee in the 1950s. Retired in the 1980s, he now (2008) owns and operates a database services company in Florida.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Fulton Lewis III Papers consist of correspondence, subject files, manuscripts, and published material.
Correspondence, both incoming and outgoing, includes fan mail as well as general correspondence. Subject files consists of lists, menus, and student papers and reports. Manuscripts includes columns and commercials as well as manuscripts of radio broadcasts. Published material contains newsletters written by Lewis and some weekly newspapers of others.
Arrangement of the Collection
Correspondence is arranged alphabetically by correspondent; fan mail is placed separately at the end of the series. Subject files are arranged alphabetically by topic. Manuscripts are arranged alphabetically by type of material; within that, radio scripts are arranged chronologically. Published material is arranged alphabetically by title.
Related Material
See also the
Fulton Lewis Jr. Papers
.
Subject and Genre Headings
Journalism; Popular culture; Radio, television, film; Lewis, Fulton, 1936-; Broadcast journalism -- United States.; Journalism.; Journalists -- United States.; Radio journalism -- United States.; Radio journalists -- United States.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Journalists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - A-H, 1966; 1967; 6 folders (Box 1)
  - Hoover, J. Edgar, 1966 (Box 1)
  - Hunt, H. L., 1966; 1967 (Box 1)
  - I-Z, unidentified, 1966; 1967; 7 folders (Box 1)
  - Fan mail
    - 1965-1966 Sep, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - 1966 Oct-1967 Dec, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Undated, circa 1966-1967 (Box 2)
    - Condolences on death of Fulton Lewis, Jr., 1966; 5 folders (Box 3)
  - Outgoing, 1966; 1967 (Box 3)
  - Of others, 1966 (Box 3)
- Subject files
  - Lists, 1954 (Box 4)
  - Menus, 1947 (Box 4)
  - Student papers and reports, 1948; 1955 (Box 4)
- Manuscripts
  - Columns (Box 4)
  - Commercials (Box 4)
  - Radio broadcasts
    - Top of the News, 1966, Aug-Oct; original typescripts (Box 4)
    - Top of the News, 1966, Nov-Dec; original typescripts and carbons (Box 5)
- Published material
  - Newsletters by Fulton Lewis III
    - Exclusive, 1966 (Box 5)
    - The Top of the News, 1967 (Box 5)
  - Weekly newspapers by others, 1967 (Box 5)